<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>early rising - Kuba Waliński</title><description>Thoughts on my life, the code I write and everything else that catches my attention...</description><link>http://kubawalinski-blog.azurewebsites.net/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2015 17:47:50 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kubawalinski-blog.azurewebsites.net/tag/early-rising/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>First!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, let me just say this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOLY CRAP, I &lt;strong&gt;FINALLY&lt;/strong&gt; HAVE MY OWN BLOG!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we've got it out of the way let me get to the point. And the point I would like to make is that &lt;strong&gt;getting up early is awesome&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
I am devoting my first post to this topic, because if I did not try getting up (very) early over the past week this blog wouldn't be here and I would still be one of those people who keep thinking about writing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never had problems with getting up early. About a year ago I started going for a swim regularly at 7AM. This meant I had to get up around 6.30AM and that was what I defined as very early at the time. I was happy with this arrangement for a while, but recently I came to the conclusion that exercising is not the best use of my morning time. I might as well exercise in the afternoon, after work, when my mind is tired and useless, but my body is still up for it. &lt;br&gt;
Years of cramming for exams and delivering projects at the last minute made me think that late at night is the time when I do my best work, but recently I started suspecting that this is just a (bad) habit. This line of thinking was reinforced when I joined ABB two months ago and started working with &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rafek"&gt;rafek&lt;/a&gt;. I was impressed with the fact that he comes to work every day at 6AM and somehow manages to stay productive and enthusiastic throughout the day. We talked about it for a while and he recommended that I have a look at &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/"&gt;Zen Habits'&lt;/a&gt; post about &lt;a href="http://zenhabits.net/10-benefits-of-rising-early-and-how-to-do-it/"&gt;10 Benefits of rising early&lt;/a&gt;. It is a great read and I wholeheartedly recommend it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those thoughts and interactions inspired me to conduct an experiment which I am just finishing by writing this post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5.00 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.40 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5.20 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.30 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5.00 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9.00 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6.00 AM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are the times at which I got out of bed this week. Apart from Saturday, when I had to recover from staying up late, I managed to maintain a very early wake up schedule throughout the whole experiment. I got a lot of stuff done this week in the hours before starting my regular workday. It was amazing! I am so happy with the results that I am going to continue, but not as an expermient anymore. This is now going to be my standard behaviour. I can't wait to see how this affects my life (in a positive way, I hope :) ). I will report back with any observations as I move forward with this plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://kubawalinski-blog.azurewebsites.net/first/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcb7eea-eff8-4ed6-9bdf-32f95db90e3e</guid><category>scrcrw</category><category>productivity</category><category>early rising</category><dc:creator>Kuba Waliński</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 07:02:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>